Ethan Holen

COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY CLASS OF 2022, B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

□720-326-5046 | Sethanholen@gmail.com | #6 ethanholen.com | GethanHolen | Gethanholen-563856174

Summary

Current research assistant, and undergraduate at Colorado State University with experience in both the software and hardware side of the tech industry. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and macOS and enjoys backpacking, mountain biking and camping in the mountains of Colorado. Interested in gaining new and interesting experiences in the field of software development.

Experience

CSU - Natural User Interaction Lab

Fort Collins CO

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May. 2020 - Present

- Currently working as a research assistant with CSU's NUILab
- Designing virtual and augmented reality environments for Research projects
- · Technologies: Unity, C#

IOS Development Denver CO

IOS DEVELOPER FOR DCSO AND MAYO CLINIC

July. 2019 - Present

- Currently working with Mayo clinic to design a custom vaccine App for patient care
- Wrote custom IOS Application for Douglas County Sheriffs Office
- Designed and Created a secure back-end using AWS Lambda and API Gateway
- Technologies: Swift, Xcode, AWS Lambda, API Gateway

Valor Christian High School

Highlands Ranch, CO. Aug. 2016 - May. 2018

IT INTERN

- Provided hardware and software solutions for help desk tickets
- Helped manage a JAMF environment of 550 Apple devices
- Setup and management of 20 Aerohive network access points

Express Care Cheyenne, WY

MEDICAL ASSISTANT

• Assisted Doctor or PA on call as a scribe

Vitals and initial patient charts, Strep, urine and vision tests

Education

COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY(COLLEGE OF NATURAL SCIENCES)

Fort Collins, CO Jan. 2019 - PRESENT

May. 2016 - Jul. 2016

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

• Relevant Coursework: Intro to Java Programming (Java), Data Structures (Java), Computer Organization (C/C++), OS and Networks (Bash), Discrete Structures and their Applications (Python), Managing Big Data (Python), Operating Systems (C), Software Development (C++)

Valor Christian High School

Highlands Ranch, CO Aug. 2014 - May. 2018

Relevant Coursework: AP Computer Science (Java), Web Design (HTML/CSS)

Other_

HackCU VI (4th Place)

Boulder, CO

Feb 22-23

- Wrote angular front end for an easy to use API creation tool.
- · Won fourth place overall in the competition. Details: https://devpost.com/software/backend-rzdbu3

Languages & Technologies

PERSONAL

MEDICAL ASSISTANT

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Bash, Swift, C, C++, C#
- Software: OSX, Windows, Linux, AWS, Xcode, Personal Website, Unity

Medical Missions Work Ethiopia

• Assisted physicians with scribe work and basic medical tests.

Video: https://govalor.com/discovery-ethiopia-video/

Eagle Scout - Troop 102

Greenwood Village, CO

PATROL LEADER, TROOP HISTORIAN

Sep. 2011 - May. 2015

Aug. 2017

- Learned Leadership and organization through positions of patrol leader and troop historian
- Project: Built a garden and fence around the local Orthodox monastery